Hello everyone and welcome to English Odd.
大家好，欢迎收听《英语奇谈》。
My name is Marco.
我是马可。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about the human body, right Marco?
我是凯瑟琳，今天我们聊的是人体，对吧，马可？
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to take a look at very specific vocabulary words related to your
今天我们要学习一些非常具体的词汇，关于你的
body, what's inside your body.
身体，你身体内部的东西。
So let's just jump right into this dialogue.
那我们就直接进入对话吧。
Let's listen to this anatomy class.
我们来听听这节解剖课。
Okay class, so today we're going to continue with our anatomy class.
好了，同学们，今天我们继续上解剖课。
Today we will review everything we have learned.
今天我们要复习所有学过的内容。
Can anyone tell me what the first major organ is?
谁能告诉我第一个主要器官是什么？
The brain.
大脑。
That's right, the brain.
没错，大脑。
It serves as a control center for the body, handling the processes of the central nervous
它充当身体的控制中心，处理中枢神经
system as well as cognition.
系统的过程以及认知功能。
Then what major organ is in our chest?
那我们胸腔里的主要器官是什么？
The heart.
心脏。
Very good.
非常好。
It pumps blood throughout the body using the circulatory system such as blood vessels and
它通过循环系统（比如血管和
veins.
静脉）将血液泵送到全身。
Now let's not forget that our lungs provide oxygen to our heart and body to keep us alive.
别忘了，我们的肺为心脏和身体提供氧气，让我们活着。
Now what about the organs that help us digest food?
那帮助我们消化食物的器官呢？
The stomach and intestines.
胃和肠道。
Very good.
非常好。
Let's not forget that the stomach is the one that breaks down our food and our intestines
别忘了，胃负责分解食物，而肠道
process the food and then expel the waste.
处理食物并排出废物。
Are we forgetting anything?
我们有没有漏掉什么？
Yeah, our kidneys, liver and bladder.
有，我们的肾脏、肝脏和膀胱。
Oh yes, you are right.
哦，对，你说得对。
Very important organs indeed.
确实是非常重要的器官。
So what do these organs do, teacher?
那这些器官是做什么的，老师？
Well, they…
嗯，它们……
Time for a break.
该休息了。
We can talk about it when you get back.
等你们回来我们再聊。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some vocab on Language Takeaway.
现在来看看“语言要点”里的词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the first word we have today is anatomy.
今天我们第一个词是“解剖学”。
We've heard this already.
我们已经听过这个词了。
This is the study of the body, right?
这是研究身体的学科，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So maybe in high school you took an anatomy class.
所以也许你在高中上过解剖课。
You studied the bodies maybe of animals, for example.
你可能研究过动物的身体，比如。
That's right.
没错。
But if we're talking about human beings, we would call it human anatomy and we would study
但如果我们说的是人类，我们会称之为人体解剖学，我们会研究
the things like your organs, your bones, all the things that make up your body.
像器官、骨骼，所有构成你身体的东西。
That's right.
没错。
And that's our next word.
这就是我们的下一个词。
We're talking about our body organs.
我们在谈论身体器官。
Now this is important.
这很重要。
Where are these located, Marco?
这些器官在哪里，马可？
Inside or outside?
里面还是外面？
Inside.
里面。
Inside the body.
身体内部。
So the body has many different organs and we learned all about these in today's dialogue.
所以身体有很多不同的器官，我们在今天的对话中都学到了。
But an organ is basically a part.
但器官基本上是一个部分。
A part of your body.
你身体的一部分。
But it has a special function or many functions.
但它有特殊的功能或多种功能。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
So for example, we talked about the heart.
比如，我们谈到了心脏。
We all know what the heart is and it's one of our main organs that pumps blood through
我们都知道心脏是什么，它是我们主要的器官之一，负责将血液泵送
our body.
到全身。
That's right.
没错。
And so some of these organs have to do with processing food.
所以有些器官与处理食物有关。
Some have to do with blood.
有些与血液有关。
But there's also an interesting system that we heard about called the central nervous
但还有一个有趣的系统我们听说过，叫做中枢神经
system.
系统。
That's right.
没错。
And this is very closely related to the brain.
这与大脑密切相关。
So basically the nervous system is in charge of all the things that you feel in your body.
所以基本上，神经系统负责你身体里所有感觉。
That's right.
没错。
So you feel through what are called nerves and the central nervous system is actually
所以你是通过所谓的神经来感觉，而中枢神经系统实际上
a system that connects all these things together and then connects it to the brain.
是一个连接所有这些部分并连接到大脑的系统。
So think of a system as being comprised of many different parts, not just one nerve.
所以把系统想象成由许多不同部分组成，而不仅仅是一根神经。
That's right.
没错。
So we're talking about, for example, your skin is part of the nervous system, your eyes,
所以我们说的是，比如，你的皮肤是神经系统的一部分，你的眼睛，
what you see, and all this gets fed into the brain and it processes it.
你看到的东西，所有这些都输入到大脑，大脑进行处理。
And that's what basically the nervous system is all about.
这就是神经系统的基本内容。
That's right.
没错。
And the brain is also important for other things.
而且大脑对其他事情也很重要。
We heard about this noun cognition.
我们听说了“认知”这个名词。
Yeah.
是的。
The doctor said, yeah, the teacher said that cognition was one of the other things that
医生说，是的，老师说认知是大脑帮助我们处理的另一件事。
the brain helped us with.
大脑帮助我们处理的事情之一。
So what exactly is cognition?
那么认知到底是什么？
Cognition is the ability to think.
认知是思考的能力。
All right.
好的。
So humans have cognition.
所以人类有认知能力。
That means we have brains and our brains allow us to think and even talk and write music
这意味着我们有大脑，大脑让我们能够思考，甚至说话、创作音乐。
and things like that.
以及类似的事情。
But for example, a rock does not have cognition.
但比如，石头就没有认知能力。
A plant would not have cognition either because they don't have this special organ, the brain
植物也没有认知能力，因为它们没有这个特殊的器官——大脑。
that allows them to think.
大脑让它们能够思考。
Right.
对。
So it's a noun, right?
所以这是一个名词，对吧？
You're saying that we have cognition because we have brains.
你是说我们有认知能力是因为我们有大脑。
That's right.
没错。
You have it.
你有这个能力。
Okay.
好的。
So those are the four words that we're going to take a look at to introduce the lesson.
所以这就是我们要看的四个词，用来引入这节课。
Why don't we move on now to more specific vocab?
我们不如继续看更具体的词汇吧？
Let's take a look at some of the main organs that we discussed in this dialogue on Language
让我们看看在“语言学习第二部分”对话中讨论的一些主要器官。
Takeaway Part 2.
在“语言学习第二部分”中讨论的一些主要器官。
Okay, class.
好了，同学们。
So today we're going to continue with our anatomy class.
今天我们要继续上解剖课。
Today we will review everything we have learned.
今天我们将复习所有学过的内容。
Can anyone tell me what the first major organ is?
谁能告诉我第一个主要器官是什么？
The brain.
大脑。
That's right.
没错。
The brain.
大脑。
It serves as a control center for the body, handling the processes of the central nervous
它是身体的控制中心，处理中枢神经系统的过程。
system as well as cognition.
以及认知功能。
Then what major organ is in our chest?
那么，我们胸腔里的主要器官是什么？
The heart.
心脏。
Very good.
很好。
It pumps blood throughout the body using the circulatory system such as blood vessels and
它通过循环系统（如血管和静脉）将血液泵送到全身。
veins.
血管和静脉。
Now, let's not forget that our lungs provide oxygen to our heart and body to keep us alive.
现在，别忘了我们的肺为心脏和身体提供氧气，让我们活着。
Now what about the organs that help us digest food?
那么帮助我们消化食物的器官呢？
The stomach and intestines.
胃和肠道。
Very good.
很好。
Let's not forget that the stomach is the one that breaks down our food and our intestines
别忘了胃负责分解食物，而肠道。
process the food and then expel the waste.
处理食物并排出废物。
Are we forgetting anything?
我们有没有遗漏什么？
Yeah.
是的。
Our kidneys, liver, and bladder.
我们的肾脏、肝脏和膀胱。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
You are right.
你说得对。
Very important organs indeed.
确实是非常重要的器官。
So what do these organs do, teacher?
那么这些器官是做什么的，老师？
Well, they...
嗯，它们……
Time for a break.
该休息了。
We can talk about it when you get back.
等你们回来我们再谈。
So we're moving down the body.
所以我们正在往下讲身体部位。
We had the brain and we mentioned the stomach.
我们讲了大脑，也提到了胃。
We had the brain and then the heart, of course, which pumps blood like you say, Marco.
我们讲了大脑，然后当然是心脏，它像你说的那样泵血，Marco。
But the next item, the next organ is the stomach.
但下一个器官是胃。
That's right.
没错。
So we get to the stomach and the intestines, which are very closely bound together.
所以我们讲到胃和肠道，它们紧密相连。
So what does the stomach do first?
那么胃首先做什么？
First of all, when you eat food, the food is sent to your stomach where your stomach
首先，当你吃东西时，食物被送到胃里，胃会分解它。
breaks it down and decides what parts to keep and what parts to save, right?
并决定保留哪些部分，储存哪些部分，对吧？
Right.
对。
And the interesting thing is that in our stomachs, we have what we call acid.
有趣的是，我们的胃里有所谓的胃酸。
Yeah.
是的。
So these acids break down those foods because it all gets mixed together in there and your
这些酸分解食物，因为所有东西都在里面混合，你的身体必须确定你吃了什么。
body has to determine what exactly you've been eating.
你的身体必须确定你吃了什么。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
So after the stomach breaks things down, it goes through the intestines and also the intestines
所以胃分解东西后，食物会经过肠道，肠道也非常重要。
are very important and they're very long, but they're all wound up inside our stomach.
它们很长，但都盘绕在我们的肚子里。
That's right.
没错。
And they kind of look like a lot of S's because they're all coiled up inside of us and they're
它们看起来像很多个S形，因为都盘绕在我们体内，确实很长。
indeed quite long.
它们确实很长。
But the intestines are also very, very important because they're actually what the waste or
但肠道也非常非常重要，因为它们实际上处理废物。
the parts of food that our bodies don't need, so they travel through to get out of our systems.
或者身体不需要的食物部分，它们通过肠道排出体外。
That's right.
没错。
So actually the intestines will absorb part of the proteins and the vitamins and everything
所以实际上肠道会吸收部分蛋白质、维生素。
that we need.
以及我们所需的一切。
And at the same time, they will also act as little tunnels that will transport the waste,
同时，它们也会像小隧道一样运输废物。
the things that we don't need to have inside our body to later be able to digest.
那些我们不需要留在体内、以便之后能消化的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So the stomach and the intestines, those have to do with the way that we eat, process and
所以胃和肠道，它们与我们进食、处理以及
dispose of food.
排泄食物的方式有关。
But now we have the kidneys.
但现在我们来说说肾脏。
Okay.
好的。
So people have two kidneys, right?
所以人有两颗肾脏，对吧？
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
People have two kidneys and actually you can continue living with just one kidney, right?
人有两颗肾脏，实际上你只靠一颗肾脏也能活下去，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
They're kind of shaped like a C almost.
它们的形状差不多像个C。
In fact, we have something called a kidney bean in English, which is a red bean and it
事实上，英语里有一种叫“kidney bean”的东西，就是一种红豆，它
looks just like a kidney.
看起来就像肾脏。
Okay.
好的。
And well, what do the kidneys do?
那么，肾脏是做什么的呢？
The kidneys from what I understand basically clean your blood.
据我所知，肾脏基本上是清洁你的血液。
So there's lots of things in your system, in your body, especially from the things that
所以你的系统里、身体里有很多东西，尤其是从你
you eat and maybe the chemicals that you're exposed to.
吃的东西和你可能接触到的化学物质中来的。
And we need our kidneys, or at least the one kidney to clean our blood and to make sure
我们需要肾脏，或者至少一颗肾脏来清洁血液，确保
our blood is what it's supposed to be.
我们的血液是正常的。
And in fact, when the kidneys aren't working properly, it's very, very serious and we call
事实上，当肾脏不能正常工作时，情况非常非常严重，我们称之为
this kidney failure, right?
肾衰竭，对吧？
So when you're watching a TV show about doctors, maybe you say, oh, he's gone into kidney failure.
所以当你看关于医生的电视剧时，你可能会说，哦，他肾衰竭了。
Right.
对。
It's a big deal, very big problem.
这是大事，非常严重的问题。
All right.
好的。
So this is what our kidneys do, a very important part of our bodies, obviously.
这就是我们肾脏的功能，显然是我们身体非常重要的一部分。
And well, as you said, they act as filters, but near the kidneys, we also have the liver.
而且，正如你所说，它们充当过滤器，但在肾脏附近，我们还有肝脏。
That's right.
没错。
And the liver is actually for some people, a delicious food, not human liver, but animal
肝脏对一些人来说，其实是美味的食物，不是人的肝脏，而是动物
liver.
肝脏。
But in humans, we also have this organ, right?
但在人体内，我们也有这个器官，对吧？
And it's also closely related to people who have drinking problems.
它也和有饮酒问题的人密切相关。
They have bad livers.
他们的肝脏不好。
And why is that?
那是为什么呢？
I think it has to do a little bit with what the liver does.
我想这和肝脏的功能有点关系。
It does many different things, but alcohol, I think harms your liver, makes it weaker.
它有很多不同的功能，但酒精，我认为会损害你的肝脏，让它变弱。
And the liver is important because it helps to generate hormones, but it also helps us
肝脏很重要，因为它有助于生成激素，但它也帮助我们
process chemicals in our body.
处理体内的化学物质。
Right.
对。
So this is really important.
所以这真的很重要。
Actually, why the liver is so important is because it does so much.
实际上，肝脏之所以如此重要，是因为它功能太多了。
And well, we only got one of them, so we can't really live without it, right?
而且，我们只有一个肝脏，所以没有它我们真的活不了，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So the liver is a very important thing.
所以肝脏是非常重要的东西。
And actually, many people now have gone through liver transplants.
实际上，现在很多人做过肝脏移植。
That means that their liver stops working, so they receive the liver of another person.
这意味着他们的肝脏停止工作了，所以他们接受另一个人的肝脏。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
So you might hear that as well on TV.
所以你在电视上也可能听到这个。
And the last organ that we took a look at here is the bladder, which is also very important,
我们这里看的最后一个器官是膀胱，它也非常重要，
goes hand in hand with the kidneys.
和肾脏密切相关。
It does.
是的。
So the bladder, you might hear someone say, I have a bad bladder.
所以膀胱，你可能会听人说，我膀胱不好。
That means that I often have to use the bathroom to go urinate.
这意味着我经常要上厕所小便。
Now the bladder is where liquids and also some kinds of chemicals in our bodies that
膀胱是我们体内液体以及某些从食物中获取的化学物质
we get from the food that we eat are kept until we dispose of them.
被储存的地方，直到我们排出它们。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
So actually when your bladder is full, because it gets full of liquid or urine, that's when
所以实际上，当你的膀胱满了，因为它装满了液体或尿液，那就是
you have to go to the bathroom.
你得上厕所的时候。
That's right.
没错。
And so pregnant women often have weaker bladders.
所以孕妇通常膀胱更弱。
They feel pressure on the bladder, so it hurts and that doesn't hurt.
她们感到膀胱有压力，所以会疼，那可不舒服。
It pushes down the bladder.
它会向下压迫膀胱。
The baby does.
是胎儿在压迫。
So they often have to pee very often, unlike people who are not pregnant.
所以她们经常要小便，不像没怀孕的人。
Okay.
好的。
Very, very interesting.
非常非常有趣。
And actually, some people say that, you know, I have a small bladder and that's why they
实际上，有些人说，你知道，我膀胱小，这就是为什么他们
go to the bathroom all the time, more often than others.
总是上厕所，比别人更频繁。
Now why don't we take a look at our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back in a bit
现在我们最后再看一遍我们的对话，一会儿我们回来
to talk a little bit more.
再聊更多。
Okay class.
好了，同学们。
So today we're going to continue with our anatomy class.
所以今天我们将继续我们的解剖课。
Today we will review everything we have learned.
今天我们将复习所有学过的内容。
Can anyone tell me what the first major organ is?
谁能告诉我第一个主要器官是什么？
The brain.
大脑。
That's right.
没错。
The brain.
大脑。
The brain is the control center for the body, handling the processes of the central nervous
大脑是身体的控制中心，负责处理中枢神经系统的过程，
system, as well as cognition.
以及认知功能。
Then what major organ is in our chest?
那我们胸腔里有什么主要器官？
The heart.
心脏。
Very good.
很好。
It pumps blood throughout the body using the circulatory system, such as blood vessels
它通过循环系统（比如血管和静脉）将血液泵送到全身。
and veins.
和静脉。
Now, let's not forget that our lungs provide oxygen to our heart and body to keep us alive.
别忘了，我们的肺为心脏和身体提供氧气，让我们活着。
Now what about the organs that help us digest food?
那帮助我们消化食物的器官呢？
The stomach and intestines.
胃和肠道。
Very good.
很好。
Let's not forget that the stomach is the one that breaks down our food and our intestines
别忘了，胃负责分解食物，而肠道
process the food and then expel the waste.
处理食物并排出废物。
Are we forgetting anything?
我们有没有漏掉什么？
Yeah.
有。
Our kidneys, liver and bladder.
我们的肾脏、肝脏和膀胱。
Oh yes, you are right.
哦，对，你说得对。
Very important organs indeed.
确实是非常重要的器官。
So what do these organs do, teacher?
老师，那这些器官是做什么的？
Well, they...
嗯，它们……
Time for a break.
该休息了。
We can talk about it when you get back.
等你回来我们再聊。
All right.
好的。
So you mentioned that actually some people get liver transplants.
所以你提到有些人确实做了肝脏移植。
So out of all these organs, we could also have a kidney transplant, right?
那么在这些器官中，我们也可以做肾脏移植，对吧？
You can donate your kidneys.
你可以捐献肾脏。
You can.
可以。
So obviously you can't have any kidney.
显然你不能随便用任何肾脏。
You actually have to have a match, someone who is the right type.
实际上必须匹配，找到合适血型的人。
But oftentimes they do perform these surgeries with the kidney transplant or a liver transplant.
但通常他们确实会进行肾脏移植或肝脏移植手术。
Now what about a heart transplant?
那心脏移植呢？
I believe they've done tests of heart transplants and they've done a few successful ones.
我相信他们做过心脏移植的试验，并且成功了一些。
Sometimes they use pieces of cow or pig hearts because they have very similar genetic makeups
有时他们会用牛或猪的心脏部分，因为它们的基因构成
to human beings.
与人类非常相似。
So they can use little pieces like valves.
所以他们可以用像瓣膜这样的小部件。
But I really don't know.
但我真的不太清楚。
I don't think they're as common as liver or kidney.
我觉得它们不像肝脏或肾脏移植那么常见。
That's right.
没错。
And actually these organs, we don't really pay too much attention to them, but they're
实际上，这些器官我们平时不太关注，但它们
so very delicate and they do so many things that actually once you only begin having some
非常脆弱，而且功能很多，一旦你开始出现
problems with them, that's when you realize how important they are.
问题，才会意识到它们有多重要。
That's right.
没错。
So it's really important to understand a little bit about how they work and also how to take
所以了解它们的工作原理以及如何保养
care of them.
真的很重要。
Because obviously if you're having liver problems, you should stop drinking so much that there
因为显然，如果你有肝脏问题，就应该少喝酒，有些
are some things that you can do to help protect yourself.
事情你可以做来保护自己。
And one that we didn't mention is actually the biggest organ that they talk about is
还有一个我们没提到的，实际上他们说的最大器官是
the skin.
皮肤。
The skin is a big organ.
皮肤是一个大器官。
Also the lungs we didn't mention.
还有肺我们也没提。
Yes, the lungs.
是的，肺。
The lungs help us breathe.
肺帮助我们呼吸。
But the skin is one of the largest parts of our body.
但皮肤是我们身体最大的部分之一。
Yes, I didn't really know that.
是的，我以前真不知道。
I didn't realize that.
我没意识到这一点。
I wasn't very good at anatomy or biology.
我解剖学或生物学学得不太好。
I wasn't really into it much.
我对这些不太感兴趣。
But I didn't realize that the skin is actually an organ just like the heart, the lungs, everything.
但我没意识到皮肤其实和心脏、肺等器官一样，也是一个器官。
Interesting.
有意思。
I hadn't thought about that.
我以前没想过这个。
It's maybe because I feel so comfortable in it.
可能是因为我太习惯它了。
I just get to see it every day.
我每天都看到它。
Yes, and it's alive.
是的，而且它是活的。
It actually breathes.
它实际上会呼吸。
We're changing skin all the time.
我们一直在换皮肤。
So it's very interesting.
所以这很有趣。
So a very medical related topic but very interesting as well because we didn't touch so many other
所以这是一个很医学相关的话题，但也很有趣，因为我们没涉及那么多其他
parts of the body.
身体部位。
For example, bones.
比如，骨头。
There are so many names of the different bones.
不同骨头有好多名字。
That's right.
没错。
And your tongue and your teeth and your eyes, all these different pieces and parts.
还有你的舌头、牙齿和眼睛，所有这些不同的部分。
So definitely more stuff that we could talk about next time.
所以下次肯定还有更多内容可以聊。
But for now we hope that you've learned something.
但现在，我们希望你们学到了一些东西。
If you have questions or comments, as always, you can come to our website englishpod.com
如果你们有问题或评论，像往常一样，可以来我们的网站 englishpod.com
and let us know.
告诉我们。
All right guys, we'll see you there.
好了，各位，我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。